<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hacking on Oh The Huge Manatee!</title>
    <link>http://ohthehugemanatee.github.io/categories/hacking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hacking on Oh The Huge Manatee!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 23:06:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://ohthehugemanatee.github.io/categories/hacking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>That time I resurrected my Linux MacBook Pro</title>
      <link>http://ohthehugemanatee.github.io/blog/2017/06/17/that-time-i-resurrected-my-linux-macbook-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 23:06:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ohthehugemanatee.github.io/blog/2017/06/17/that-time-i-resurrected-my-linux-macbook-pro/</guid>
      <description>In the airport last week, my laptop stopped booting.
I have a 2012 Macbook Pro - yes, that coveted &amp;ldquo;last good model&amp;rdquo; - and it runs Ubuntu Linux. It&amp;rsquo;s my roving office as I travel the world to conferences, performances, and job sites. So when I started it up at JFK airport this week and got a gray screen of death, I was a little concerned.
I tried starting into Startup Manager by holding the &amp;ldquo;Option&amp;rdquo; key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How and why to update the modem/baseband firmware on a Samsung Android phone</title>
      <link>http://ohthehugemanatee.github.io/blog/2015/04/04/how-and-why-to-update-the-modem-slash-baseband-firmware-on-a-samsung-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2015 08:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ohthehugemanatee.github.io/blog/2015/04/04/how-and-why-to-update-the-modem-slash-baseband-firmware-on-a-samsung-phone/</guid>
      <description>If you have a Samsung Android phone, and you use Samsung&amp;rsquo;s own version of Android, this article is not for you. When Samsung sends you updates to Android, they also will include any relevant updates to the modem/baseband firmware. So stop reading and go have a cup of tea or something, your job is done.
But for everyone who uses a custom ROM like Cyanogenmod, ParanoidAndroid, or AOKP, sit up and pay attention: you&amp;rsquo;re missing some key updates for your phone, and it&amp;rsquo;s probably the reason you have trouble with cellular signal or battery life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to recover photos and data from a keylocked Android phone</title>
      <link>http://ohthehugemanatee.github.io/blog/2014/05/18/recovering-photos-and-data-from-a-keylocked-android-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2014 18:55:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ohthehugemanatee.github.io/blog/2014/05/18/recovering-photos-and-data-from-a-keylocked-android-phone/</guid>
      <description>Recently a good friend of mine passed away suddenly. Her family asked me to recover her photos and videos from her computer and android phone. The computer was easy enough, but the android phone posed a real problem. It had a keylock enabled, and USB debugging disabled. There was no external SD card to pull out, which meant that all the photos were stored on the internal memory. The phone was a totally stock Samsung Galaxy S3 mini.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
