<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>wifi on Oh The Huge Manatee!</title>
    <link>https://ohthehugemanatee.org/categories/wifi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in wifi on Oh The Huge Manatee!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2011 12:19:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ohthehugemanatee.org/categories/wifi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Still more wireless troubleshooting</title>
      <link>https://ohthehugemanatee.org/2011/03/still-more-wireless-troubleshooting.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2011 12:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohthehugemanatee.org/2011/03/still-more-wireless-troubleshooting.html</guid>
      <description>{% raw %} The damnedest thing happened - I went out of town. &amp;nbsp;I went out of town, and discovered that I was STILL getting dropouts every 90 seconds! &amp;nbsp;On a totally different router, on the opposite site of the planet, in a rural area with no conceivable wireless interference. &amp;nbsp;This prompted me to boot into Windows 7 (I have a Boot Camp partition) to try my ping test under a totally different software stack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More DD-WRT / Linksys WRT54G troubleshooting</title>
      <link>https://ohthehugemanatee.org/2010/12/more-dd-wrt-linksys-wrt54g.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2010 00:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohthehugemanatee.org/2010/12/more-dd-wrt-linksys-wrt54g.html</guid>
      <description>{% raw %} After my evening spent getting my DD-WRT firmware to a stable version (as opposed to the version recommended by the DD-WRT website), I had hoped that I had seen the end of my wireless issues.
No such luck.
I have definitely seen an improvement - in a ping flood test, I&#39;m only seeing 0.5% dropped packets now, which is an improvement over the 2% I was seeing before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DD-WRT, versioning, and the Linksys WRT54G wireless router</title>
      <link>https://ohthehugemanatee.org/2010/12/dd-wrt-versioning-and-linksys-wrt54g.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2010 12:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohthehugemanatee.org/2010/12/dd-wrt-versioning-and-linksys-wrt54g.html</guid>
      <description>{% raw %} I have had all sorts of trouble with the wireless situation in my apartment. &amp;nbsp;The layout of the place is such that the kitchen sits in between the two major rooms (living room and bedroom), and I swear those kitchen walls must be made of lead. &amp;nbsp;No wireless signal seems to get through. &amp;nbsp;I have phone jacks for ADSL in the living room and bedroom, nothing in between.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
