<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PHP on Oh The Huge Manatee!</title>
    <link>https://ohthehugemanatee.org/categories/php/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PHP on Oh The Huge Manatee!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 12:03:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ohthehugemanatee.org/categories/php/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The 3 skills you need to become a rock star developer</title>
      <link>https://ohthehugemanatee.org/blog/2017/08/04/the-only-3-tools-you-need-to-become-a-rock-star-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 12:03:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohthehugemanatee.org/blog/2017/08/04/the-only-3-tools-you-need-to-become-a-rock-star-developer/</guid>
      <description>A lot is made of so-called &amp;ldquo;rockstar developers&amp;rdquo; in any given language or framework. They have a seemingly magical knowledge of the language and API, finding obscure methods and writing best-practice code as if by instinct. I&amp;rsquo;d like to lift the curtain on this: it&amp;rsquo;s not that hard to be this kind of rock star. You can do it, too&amp;hellip; even without a fancy computer science degree. If you know how to code in a given language, you just need 3 skills and some patience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why no mainstream PHP speakers come to Drupalcon - and how we&#39;re changing that</title>
      <link>https://ohthehugemanatee.org/blog/2017/07/28/bring-php-to-drupalcon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 17:01:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohthehugemanatee.org/blog/2017/07/28/bring-php-to-drupalcon/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve learned something incredible as the PHP Track Chair for Drupalcon Vienna. The Drupal Association has no way to invite PHP speakers to Drupalcon.
This blew me away when I first learned about it. After all the work to bring mainstream PHP to Drupal core, after all the outreach to PHP-FIG, after all the talks Drupalists have given at major PHP conferences, how is this possible?
You see, basically every other PHP conference covers their speakers&amp;rsquo; travel and accommodation costs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better PHP === Better Drupalists: the PHP track at Drupalcon Vienna</title>
      <link>https://ohthehugemanatee.org/blog/2017/06/15/better-php-better-drupalists/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 17:19:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohthehugemanatee.org/blog/2017/06/15/better-php-better-drupalists/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the best parts of Drupal 8 is our shift to enterprise PHP coding structures. With tools like composer and Symfony&amp;rsquo;s structures like Events and Dependency Injection, Drupalists are learning to be great PHP developers, and vice-versa. Today, the fastest route to becoming a rock star Drupalist is through PHP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m one of the PHP track chairs for Drupalcon Vienna, and this year our focus is &lt;em&gt;better PHP === better Drupalists&lt;/em&gt;. How can better PHP make your life as a Drupal developer easier?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the world sees Drupal - the Dutch PHP Conference 2015</title>
      <link>https://ohthehugemanatee.org/blog/2015/06/27/dutch-php-conference-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 12:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohthehugemanatee.org/blog/2015/06/27/dutch-php-conference-2015/</guid>
      <description>One of the most exciting parts about the switch to Drupal 8 is the rapprochement of the Drupal community with the rest of PHP. This weekend I spoke at the Dutch PHP Conference in Amsterdam, where I got to be part of the vanguard of Drupalists reconnecting with the larger PHP world. The experience had a big impact on my perspective of the future of Drupal as a platform and as a community.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
