<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ssl on Oh The Huge Manatee!</title>
    <link>http://ohthehugemanatee.github.io/categories/ssl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ssl on Oh The Huge Manatee!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 May 2011 21:58:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://ohthehugemanatee.github.io/categories/ssl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Secure LDAP on Ubuntu 10.04 - the idiot&#39;s guide to SSL, TLS, and SLAPD</title>
      <link>http://ohthehugemanatee.github.io/2011/05/setting-up-secure-ldap-on-ubuntu-1004.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2011 21:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ohthehugemanatee.github.io/2011/05/setting-up-secure-ldap-on-ubuntu-1004.html</guid>
      <description>{% raw %} LDAP is one of the Elder Gods of the UNIX world. &amp;nbsp;It had it&#39;s beginnings in DAP, the first Directory Access Protocol, in 1988. &amp;nbsp;Within a decade DAP was more or less discarded in favor of the Lightweight Directory Access Protocol. &amp;nbsp;And it has stayed in basically the same format ever since.
LDAP is, as you might have guessed, a directory protocol. &amp;nbsp;It was developed in response to X.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Load Balancer SSL limitations</title>
      <link>http://ohthehugemanatee.github.io/2011/04/aws-load-balancer-ssl-limitations.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2011 13:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ohthehugemanatee.github.io/2011/04/aws-load-balancer-ssl-limitations.html</guid>
      <description>{% raw %} No one else seems to have documented this anywhere, so I&#39;m gonna do it here.
Amazon Web Services has a great little load balancer system you can use. &amp;nbsp;A few clicks, and you&#39;re away to the races with a shiny load balancer of your own! &amp;nbsp;The best part? &amp;nbsp;It will even do SSL termination at the load balancer for you. &amp;nbsp;Just paste in your certs and away you go!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple SSL sites on one AWS instance</title>
      <link>http://ohthehugemanatee.github.io/2011/04/multiple-ssl-sites-on-one-aws-instance.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2011 13:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ohthehugemanatee.github.io/2011/04/multiple-ssl-sites-on-one-aws-instance.html</guid>
      <description>{% raw %} It&#39;s a familiar problem - you can&#39;t really host multiple SSL sites on a single IP address. &amp;nbsp;There&#39;s a fancy workaround if you get a pricey multi-domain certificate, of course. &amp;nbsp;But separate sites, with separate certificates just won&#39;t work. &amp;nbsp;The reason is simple - put yourself in Apache&#39;s shoes.
When you&#39;re using name based virtualhosts, Apache uses the request headers to determine which vhost should get the request.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
