<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Oh The Huge Manatee!</title>
  <link href="https://ohthehugemanatee.org/index.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://ohthehugemanatee.org/"/>
  <updated>2019-10-08T19:10:15+00:00</updated>
  <id>https://ohthehugemanatee.org/</id>
  <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blogs]]></title>
    <link href="https://ohthehugemanatee.org/blog/"/>
    <id>https://ohthehugemanatee.org/blog/</id>
    <published>2019-10-08T19:10:15+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-10-08T19:10:15+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[]]></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[About me]]></title>
    <link href="https://ohthehugemanatee.org/about/"/>
    <id>https://ohthehugemanatee.org/about/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My name is Campbell Vertesi; I’m a principal lead software engineer with Microsoft, and an opera singer.</p>
<p>I’ve been working with computers for 23 years. I started with desktop repair, moved into sysadmin work, and eventually discovered Drupal 4.1 and the beginnings of the web application world. Since then I’ve been in most roles in the web consultant ecosystem: coder, themer, project manager, information architect, technical lead, CEO, and CTO. I’ve presented at dozens of software conferences, often on the main stage or as a keynote.</p>
<p>I’ve been fortunate enough to work with great organizations like the Jane Goodall Institute, the Mozilla Foundation, the EPA, the United Way, and Oxfam International. I’ve helped out big commercial organizations like Intel, Ringier Axel Springer, and Volkswagen. I&rsquo;ve contributed to many open source projects along the way.</p>
<p>The rest of the stuff I do is scattered around the Internet and real life. I’m co-founder of the opera band <a href="https://thecastmusic.com/">The Cast</a>, bringing crowds to their feet with awesome classical music. I speak English, French, Italian, and German, and I love to travel. I love to learn anything new, so I get hobbies like most people get colds. I have three awesome kids, and a great life here in Berlin, Germany. You can find out more about me and these other interests at <a href="https://campbell.vertesi.com/">campbell.vertesi.com</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
</feed>
